<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://fast.tk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://fast.tk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-06-08T23:43:20-05:00</updated><id>https://fast.tk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">fast.tk blog</title><subtitle>Yet another github hosted static blog with support for Jupyter Notebooks.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Review - Effects of Reward on Intrinsic Motivation</title><link href="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/06/08/Review-Reward-on-Intrinsic-motivation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review - Effects of Reward on Intrinsic Motivation" /><published>2021-06-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-06-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/06/08/Review-Reward-on-Intrinsic-motivation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/06/08/Review-Reward-on-Intrinsic-motivation.html">&lt;p&gt;Eisenberger, Robert, W David Pierce, and Judy Cameron. “Effects of Reward on Intrinsic Motivation—Negative, Neutral, and Positive: Comment on Deci, Koestner, and Ryan (1999),” n.d., 15. https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.125.6.677.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Meta-analyses indicated that rewards increase perceived self-determination and that rewards’ effects on intrinsic motivation depend on the performance requirement. Reward for meeting vague performance standards reduced the subsequent choice to carry out the task and did not affect self-reported interest. Reward for meeting absolute performance standards did not affect free choice but increased self-reported interest. Reward for exceeding others increased both free choice and self-reported interest. Applied studies commonly found positive or null relationships between reward and intrinsic motivation. The findings suggest that reward procedures requiring ill-defined or minimal performance convey task triviality, thereby decreasing intrinsic motivation. Reward procedures requiring specific high task performance convey a task’s personal or social significance, increasing intrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-arguments&quot;&gt;Main Arguments:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meta-analysis &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (Cameron and Pierce, 1994) in contrast to Deci (1999), argues that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reward can decrease, no effect or increase intrinsic motivation depending on it’s presented&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;General Interest Theory predicts that reward increases perceived self-determination&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reward could have positive or null effects on intrinsic motivation (specific performance requirements have more postive reward effects than do vague performance requirements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reward procedures conveying a task’s triviality decrease intrinsic motivation, whereas conveying personal or social significance increase intrinsic motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General Interest theory is proposed which holds that task content and context, including rewards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;decrease intrinsic motivation when they convey task’s irrelevance or inconsistency with the satisfaction of needs, wants or desires&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;increase intrinsic motivation when they indicate taks performance helps satisfy needs, wants or desires.
Reward’s symbolic value influences intrinsic motivation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cameron, Judy, and W. David Pierce. “Reinforcement, Reward, and Intrinsic Motivation: A Meta-Analysis.” Review of Educational Research 64, no. 3 (September 1994): 363–423. https://doi.org/10.3102/00346543064003363. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html">Eisenberger, Robert, W David Pierce, and Judy Cameron. “Effects of Reward on Intrinsic Motivation—Negative, Neutral, and Positive: Comment on Deci, Koestner, and Ryan (1999),” n.d., 15. https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.125.6.677.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review Motivational Synergy</title><link href="https://fast.tk/2021/06/02/Review-Motivational-Synergy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review Motivational Synergy" /><published>2021-06-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-06-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://fast.tk/2021/06/02/Review--Motivational-Synergy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fast.tk/2021/06/02/Review-Motivational-Synergy.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;review---motivational-synergy-toward-new-conceptualizations-of-intrinsic-and-extrinsic-motivation-in-the-workplace&quot;&gt;Review - MOTIVATIONAL SYNERGY: TOWARD NEW CONCEPTUALIZATIONS OF INTRINSIC AND EXTRINSIC MOTIVATION IN THE WORKPLACE&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amabile, Teresa M., Karl G. Hill, Beth A. Hennessey, Elizabeth M. Tighe, and Teresa M. Amabile. “The Work Preference Inventory: Assessing Intrinsic and Extrinsic Motivational Orientations. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology.” Journal of Applied Psychology, 1994, 10–1037.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The foundation for a model of motivational synergy is presented. Building upon but going beyond previous conceptualizations, the model outlines the ways in which intrinsic motivation (which arises from the intrinsic value of the work for the individual) might interact with extrinsic motivation (which arises from the desire to obtain outcomes that are apart from the work itself 1.In a modification of the prevailing psychological view that extrinsic motivation undermines intrinsic motivation, this conceptualization proposes that certain types of extrinsic motivation can combine synergistically with intrinsic motivation, particularly when initial levels of intrinsic motivation are high. Such synergistic motivational combinations should lead to high levels of employee satisfaction and performance. Two mechanisms are proposed for these combinations: extrinsics in service of intrinsics, and the motivation-work cycle match. Personality and work-environment influences on motivation are discussed, and implications are outlined for management practice and management development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaways&quot;&gt;Takeaways:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The predominant psychological view maintains that extrinsic motivation works against intrinsic motivation. Some theories differ in their conceptualizations of whether and how the two types of motivation combine. Herzberg, like Maslow in his needs-hierarchy theory, appears to view intrinsic and extrinsic motivation as combining additively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper argues that certain types of extrinsic motivation can combine synergistically with intrinsic motivation. The author’s Work Preference Inventory (WPI) measure and related research suggest that motivation orientation operates like a relatively stable personal trait, with individual differences and preferences. Intrinsic and extrinsic motivation are essentially uncorrelated. The intrinsic items clustered onto two scales, labeled Challenge and Enjoyment. The extrinsic items also clustered onto two scales, labeled Recognition and Compensation. i.e. some people could be motivated by both money and personal challenge in their work; evidence suggested that the creativity of the artist’s body of work could be positively correlated with both a challenge orientation (intrinsic) and a recognition orientation (extrinsic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it does not seem that intrinsic and extrinsic motivation operate in a simple additive fashion or in simple opposition. Intrinsic and extrinsic motivation as both a temporary state and a stable personality trait can interact with work environment in both directions. The effects could vary dramatically depend on individual personalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some types of extrinsic motivators serve to undermine intrinsic motivation and certain aspects of performance (such as creativity), but others that serve to support it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the initial level of intrinsic motivation is high, it is relatively impervious to the undermining effects of extrinsic motivators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;Synergistic&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;strong&gt;Extrinsic in Service of Intrinsic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any extrinsic factors that support one’s sense of competence without undermining one’s sense of self-determination should positively contribute to intrinsic motivation. Monetary reward itself does not necessarily undermine intrinsic motivation and creativity. But reward that signifies or is accompanied by constraint can have serious detrimental effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Motivation-Work Cycle Match:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intrinsic motivation may be most important at the problem presentation and idea generation stages, and less important at the other stages. Intrinsic motivation may be essential for novelty in the work, but some degree of some types extrinsic motivation can help to ensure that the output will be timely, complete, and useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Intrinsic and extrinsic motivation can combine positively, but not according to the simple scaffolding proposed by the need theories of Maslow (1943) and Herzberg (1966). It is not that intrinsic and extrinsic motivators are completely separate systems where one (the extrinsic) must be taken care of before the other (the intrinsic) can become operative. Rather, extrinsic motivation can, under some circumstances, complement intrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Extrinsic motivation is most likely to combine synergistically with intrinsic motivation when the initial level of intrinsic motivation is high.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Only certain types of extrinsic motivators can combine synergistically with intrinsic motivation. These synergistic extrinsic motivators provide information about the individual’s competence and the value of the product without undermining feelings of self-determination, or directly allow increased autonomy or involvement in intrinsically interesting tasks. Note the contrast between this view and that of Hackman and Oldham (1980). They propose that extrinsic motivators combine positively with only one particular form of intrinsic motivation, which they call “internal motivation”-the rewarding feeling of having done well on a challenging task. By contrast, the present proposition holds that particular forms of extrinsic motivation combine positively with all forms of intrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Certain types of extrinsic motivators will not add positively to intrinsic motivation, and will often detract from it. These non-synergistic extrinsic motivators are those that lead individuals to feel controlled or constrained by external forces.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Job satisfaction will depend on the extent to which the motivators available in the work environment (both intrinsic and extrinsic) match the individual’s basic motivational orientation toward work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Work performance depends (in addition to skill and contextual factors) on the individual’s level and type of motivation. A high level of technical quality (appropriateness) in the output requires a high degree of either intrinsic or extrinsic motivation (or both). A high level of novelty in the output requires a high degree of intrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even a high initial degree of intrinsic motivation toward one’s work can, over time, be undermined by a work environment that is unsupportive of intrinsic involvement in the work and that places a heavy emphasis on extrinsic motivators.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For individuals whose work involves complex, ongoing projects, a combination of intrinsic motivation and appropriately-timed synergistic extrinsic motivation may lead to the highest levels of creative, productive work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Review - MOTIVATIONAL SYNERGY: TOWARD NEW CONCEPTUALIZATIONS OF INTRINSIC AND EXTRINSIC MOTIVATION IN THE WORKPLACE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review The Work Preference Inventory</title><link href="https://fast.tk/2021/06/01/Review-The-Work-Preference-Inventory.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review The Work Preference Inventory" /><published>2021-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://fast.tk/2021/06/01/Review-The-Work-Preference-Inventory</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fast.tk/2021/06/01/Review-The-Work-Preference-Inventory.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;review---the-work-preference-inventory-_-assessing-intrinsic-and-extrinsic-motivational-orientations&quot;&gt;Review - The Work Preference Inventory _ Assessing Intrinsic and Extrinsic Motivational Orientations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amabile, Teresa M., Karl G. Hill, Beth A. Hennessey, Elizabeth M. Tighe, and Teresa M. Amabile. “The Work Preference Inventory: Assessing Intrinsic and Extrinsic Motivational Orientations. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology.” Journal of Applied Psychology, 1994, 10–1037.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Work Preference Inventory (WPI) is designed to assess individual differences in intrinsic and extrinsic motivational orientations. Both the college student and the working adult versions aim to capture the major elements of intrinsic motivation (self-determination, competence, task involvement, curiosity, enjoyment, and interest) and extrinsic motivation (concerns with competition, evaluation, recognition, money or other tangible incentives, and constraint by others). The instrument is scored on two primary scales, each subdivided into 2 secondary scales. The WPI has meaningful factor structures, adequate internal consistency, good short-term test-retest reliability, and good longer term stability. Moreover, WPI scores are related in meaningful ways to other questionnaire and behavioral measures of motivation, as well as personality characteristics, attitudes, and behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaways&quot;&gt;Takeaways:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WPI measures is designed to capture all the major elements of both intrinsic and extrinsic motivation orientation as a personal trait. Factor analysis established extrinsic and intrinsic motivation as primary scales, and sub-class secondary scales of Challenge and Enjoyment in intrinsic factor and Compensation and Outward secondary sub-factors in extrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relative stability of the WPI scores over 6 to 54 months interval implies WPI can be considered as a stable personal trait/preference, an enduring individual-differences characteristic. Correlations were found with other personality, attitudes and perception measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intrinsic and extrinsic are distinct, independent process. One type of motivation does not necessarily undermine the other. Highly intrinsic motivated individual can also be highly motivated by extrinsic compensation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals could be divided into four types: dually motivated, intrinsically motivated, extrinsically motivated, and unmotivated. Unlike people who are primarily intrinsically or primarily extrinsically motivated, those strongly motivated by both should experience synergistic effects on performance and satisfaction when working on tasks where both types of motivators are salient. On the other hand, dually motivated individuals might be the only ones to experience conflict when faced with a choice between a strongly intrinsically motivated activity and a strongly extrinsically motivated one. Thus, motivational orientation identification with the WPI might help to illuminate some of the motivational boosts and conflicts that people experience in their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fast.tk/assets/img/2021-06-01-Review-The-Work-Preference-Inventory/media/image1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Review - The Work Preference Inventory _ Assessing Intrinsic and Extrinsic Motivational Orientations</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review - Free Revealing and the Private-Collective Model for Innovation Incentives</title><link href="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/25/Review-Free-revealing-and-the-private-collective-model-for-innovation-incentives.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review - Free Revealing and the Private-Collective Model for Innovation Incentives" /><published>2021-05-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/25/Review-Free-revealing-and-the-private--collective-model-for-innovation-incentives</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/25/Review-Free-revealing-and-the-private-collective-model-for-innovation-incentives.html">&lt;p&gt;Hippel, Eric von, and Georg von Krogh. “Free Revealing and the Private-Collective Model for Innovation Incentives.” R and D Management 36, no. 3 (June 2006): 295–306. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9310.2006.00435.x&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A central tenant of open innovation is free revealing of the detailed workings of novel products and services, so that others may use them, learn from them, and perhaps improve them as well. We explain that innovators frequently do freely reveal proprietary information and knowledge regarding both information-based products and physical products they have developed. We explain why free revealing can make good economic sense for innovators and for society as well. The article develops the case for free revealing in terms of a ‘private collective’ model of innovation incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-arguments&quot;&gt;Main Arguments:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collective inventions (Allen, 1983) provide early evidences of free revealing in 19th century English Iron Industry and Mine Engine design (Nuvolari, 2004) in physical products. Free revealing is wide-spread in other industrial, medical, sports equipment products, while open source software depends on free revealing of the source code to exist, sometimes this kind of intentional and routine &lt;em&gt;irrational&lt;/em&gt; behaviors even take place regardless of the competing relationship among the profit-seeking firms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some practical cases could be made to explain the free revealing for innovation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When others know something close to ‘your’ secret, it’s very possible that many firms and individuals may have similar information (inevitable innovations), cost to maintain your trade secret could become too high to be practical.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When profits from patenting are low, i.e. weak appropriability to profit directly from the temporary monopoly granted from patent (Teece, 2003).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When incentives for free revealing are positive:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Free revealing help to create awareness about the innovation (increased adoption, network effect)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;increase the rate of collective learning, rapid development of better design (quickly become dominant design to preempt competitions)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;It’s hard to control the knowledge, given free-flowing of engineers and supply chain cooperation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Reputation gained from free-revealing, increased value and potential profit from related complementary assets&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Sharing enable manufacturers and users community collectively improve the innovation both up and down stream, ultimately helps everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the observation, a private-collective model of innovation incentive is proposed to account for the limit in Private Investment and Collective Action model dichotomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../images/free.revealing.table2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Table #2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-assumption&quot;&gt;Key Assumption:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovators gain more profits than free riders from freely-revealed innovations because some sources of profit remain private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Participation in the community brings intrinsic private benefits, such as learning, enjoyment and sense of ownership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adopting the private-collective model will bring the “best of both worlds” in which public goods are produced at private expense. Innovators relinquish control of knowledge produced, but at the same time gain private profits, so public subsidy is not required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The distinction between collective action model and private-collective model is the assumption that innovators profit more than free-rider, since the intrinsic rewards also exist in collective action model, can we measure the specific additional extrinsic private profit?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The happy middle ground that offer society “the best of the both worlds” seems too good to be obtained without any cost/efforts, what’s the catch? When will it fail?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;David Teece (1986) introduced the decision tree model for integration vs. contract for profiting from innovation, given the conditions of complementary assets and appropriability regime. What are firm’s best strategy to profit from open user innovation? When to free reveal as a strategy/weapon?
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Google does OSS right. Open source to commoditize your competitor's advantages, not to strengthen your own. [By anonymous]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allen, R.C. (1983) Collective invention. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 4, 1, 1–24.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nuvolari, A. (2004) Collective invention during the British industrial revolution: the case of the Cornish pumping engine. Cambridge Journal of Economics, 28, 3, 99–119.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teece, David. “Profiting from Technological Innovation: Implications for Integration, Collaboration, Licensing and Public Policy.” Research Papers in Economics, 2003, pp. 11–46.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html">Hippel, Eric von, and Georg von Krogh. “Free Revealing and the Private-Collective Model for Innovation Incentives.” R and D Management 36, no. 3 (June 2006): 295–306. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9310.2006.00435.x</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review - Myths of Intrinsic Motivation</title><link href="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/24/Review-Myths-of-intrinsic-motivation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review - Myths of Intrinsic Motivation" /><published>2021-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/24/Review-Myths-of-intrinsic-motivation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/24/Review-Myths-of-intrinsic-motivation.html">&lt;p&gt;Reiss, Steven. Myths of Intrinsic Motivation, 2013. ISBN: 978-0-9891701-0-9&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;absctract&quot;&gt;Absctract:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One scientist’s answer to Daniel Pink’s book, Drive, which claims that extrinsic incentives – money, bonuses, praise, and recognition – have the paradoxical effect of lessening intrinsic motivation. Reiss cites multiple flaws with the underlying science, discusses studies and scholarly literature reviews not mentioned in Pink’s book, and cites respected researchers who do not believe that extrinsic incentives undermine intrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-arguments&quot;&gt;Main arguments:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term undermining theory refers collectively to self-perception theory, overjustifcation theory, cognitive evaluation theory, and self-determination theory in social psychology, which predict the use of rewards and incentives undermines intrinsic motivation, and view rewards, bonus, and incentives are perceived as efforts to control. Reiss believe the undermining effect are simply well-know negative effects of rewards, such as distraction, performance anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Criticisms of social psychology of motivation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extrinsic motivation have no construct validity, three components distinguishing between intrinsic and extrinsic motivation do not exist:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;(extrinsic) means versus (intrinsic) ends: means drive their motivational properties from ends&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;(intrinsic) psychological versus (extrinsic) biological needs: Cognition brain science says every need is part biological and part psychological. There’s only one reward mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;the analysis of psychological needs as competence, autonomy and relatedness is arbitrary&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No reliable and valid measures of the distinction between intrinsic and extrinsic motivation:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results of behavioral freechoice assessments depend on the available options in the environment in which the assessments are conducted. The measures of intrinsic vs. extrinsic motivation are open to circular interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The studies lacked adequate experimental controls and scientific robustness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The studies confounded the controlling and distracting aspects of rewards. Reiss and Sushinsky (1975, 1976) suggested that undermining effects can be reinterpreted as annoying distractions conditioned to the task through Pavlovian association.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Claims of practical significance for education and business are greatly exaggerated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost all studies are distracting reward given once, the long term effect is still not clear. The theory cannot imply that base salaries can undermine intrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most people are not motivated by self-determination until it is taken away. They sometimes may view rewards as controlling, but it is much more common for people to see their pursuit of rewards and incentives as freely determined. Eisenberger et al. (1999) were right when they wrote “reward increases perceived self-determination” (p. 677). Evaluating the effects of reward on task interest is worth pursuing. It is best studied, however, without distinguishing between intrinsic and extrinsic motivation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reiss, S., &amp;amp; Sushinsky, L.W. (1976). Te competing response hypothesis of decreased play effects: A reply to Lepper and Greene. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 33, 233-244.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reiss, S., &amp;amp; Sushinsky, L.W. (1975). Overjustifcation, competing responses, and the acquisition of intrinsic interest. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 31, 1116-1125&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eisenberger, R., Pierce, W. P. &amp;amp; Camerson, J. (1999). Effects of rewards on intrinsic motivation – Negative, neutral, and positive: Comment on Deci, Koestner, and Ryan (1999). Psychological Bulletin, 125, 677-691.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html">Reiss, Steven. Myths of Intrinsic Motivation, 2013. ISBN: 978-0-9891701-0-9</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review - Why Hackers Do What They Do - Understanding Motivation and Effort in Free/Open Source Software Projects</title><link href="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/23/Review-Why-Hacker-do-what-they-do.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review - Why Hackers Do What They Do - Understanding Motivation and Effort in Free/Open Source Software Projects" /><published>2021-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/23/Review-Why-Hacker-do-what-they-do</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/23/Review-Why-Hacker-do-what-they-do.html">&lt;p&gt;Lakhani, Karim, and Robert G. Wolf. “Why Hackers Do What They Do: Understanding Motivation and Effort in Free/Open Source Software Projects.” SSRN Electronic Journal, 2003. https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.443040.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this paper we report on the results of a study of the effort and motivations of individuals to contributing to the creation of Free/Open Source software. We used a Web-based survey, administered to 684 software developers in 287 F/OSS projects, to learn what lies behind the effort put into such projects. Academic theorizing on individual motivations for participating in F/OSS projects has posited that external motivational factors in the form of extrinsic benefits (e.g.: better jobs, career advancement) are the main drivers of effort. We find in contrast, that enjoyment-based intrinsic motivation, namely how creative a person feels when working on the project, is the strongest and most pervasive driver. We also find that user need, intellectual stimulation derived from writing code, and improving programming skills are top motivators for project participation. A majority of our respondents are skilled and experienced professionals working in IT-related jobs, with approximately 40 percent being paid to participate in the F/OSS project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-arguments&quot;&gt;Main arguments:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Respondents were primarily male (97.5%) with an average age of 30 years and living primarily in the developed Western world, 58% of the respondents were directly involved in the IT industry.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“paid contributors” consisting of approximately 40% of the sample, Overall, paid contributors are spending more than two working days a week and volunteer contributors are spending more than a day a week on F/OSS projects.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All three major categories of motivations are confirmed to present in OSS participation:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;enjoyment-based intrinsic motivations&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;obligation/community-based intrinsic motivations&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;extrinsic motivations.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;User needs&lt;/em&gt; for the software, is the overwhelming reason for contribution and participation. The top single reason to contribute to projects is based on enjoyment-related intrinsic motivation, “Project code is &lt;em&gt;intellectually stimulating&lt;/em&gt; to write” (44.9%). &lt;em&gt;Improving programming skills&lt;/em&gt;, an extrinsic motivation related to human capital improvement, was a close second (41.8%). &lt;em&gt;Self-identification&lt;/em&gt; with the hacker community and ethic drive participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A sense of personal creativity is the biggest determinant of effort in F/OSS projects, this sense of creativity is endogenous and heterogeneous to the people within projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are significant differences in motivations between paid contributors and volunteers, contrary to experimental findings on the negative impact of extrinsic rewards on intrinsic motivations, dominant motives do not crowd out or spoil others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There was no significant impact on the hours per week dedicated based on the interaction of being paid and feeling creative. Hours per week dedicated to a project did not decline given, that those who are paid to contribute code are also feeling creative in that project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There should be a lot of research opportunities using OSS community, survey or NLP and SNA based analysis, given the aboudant activity data in OSS community fourm and code repositories. It would be also interesting to do meta-analysis with these types of studies, track the changes over time, as some organization like Linux Foundation do annual FOSS Contributor Survey.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are already significant differences seen between paid contributors and volunteers, better ways to distinguish them and more comparisons should reveal interesting findings.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The observation that clusters of individuals motivated by extrinsic, intrinsic, or hybrid extrinsic/intrinsic factors probably mean that there are other intrinsic needs behind the extrinsic motivations &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Reiss, Steven. Myths of Intrinsic Motivation, 2013. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html">Lakhani, Karim, and Robert G. Wolf. “Why Hackers Do What They Do: Understanding Motivation and Effort in Free/Open Source Software Projects.” SSRN Electronic Journal, 2003. https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.443040.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review - Profiting from Voluntary Information Spillovers - How Users Benefit by Freely Revealing Their Innovations</title><link href="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/22/Review-Profiting-from-voluntary-information-spillovers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review - Profiting from Voluntary Information Spillovers - How Users Benefit by Freely Revealing Their Innovations" /><published>2021-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/22/Review-Profiting-from-voluntary-information-spillovers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/22/Review-Profiting-from-voluntary-information-spillovers.html">&lt;p&gt;Harhoff, Dietmar, Joachim Henkel, and Eric von Hippel. “Profiting from Voluntary Information Spillovers: How Users Benefit by Freely Revealing Their Innovations.” Research Policy 32, no. 10 (December 2003): 1753–69. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0048-7333(03)00061-1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Empirical studies of innovation have found that end users frequently develop important product and process innovations. Defying conventional wisdom on the negative effects of uncompensated spillovers, innovative users also often openly reveal their innovations to competing users and to manufacturers. Rival users are thus in a position to reproduce the innovation in-house and benefit from using it, and manufacturers are in a position to refine the innovation and sell it to all users, including competitors of the user revealing its innovation. In this paper, we explore the incentives that users might have to freely reveal their proprietary innovations. We then develop a game-theoretic model to explore the effect of these incentives on users’ decisions to reveal or hide their proprietary information. We find that, under realistic parameter constellations, free revealing pays. We conclude by discussing some implications of our findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-arguments&quot;&gt;Main Arguments:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analysis from a game theory economics model shows that under reasonable parameter settings, free revealing of innovation via manufacturers can be profitable for the innovators (with complementary capabilities/assets).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With relative low competition, high generality of the innovation, manufacturer’s increased capability to improve the innovation and lower the cost promotes both the free-revealing and the adoption of the innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This model is also applicable to user-to-user transfers in which the receiving user creates an externality enjoyed by the sender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-assumptions&quot;&gt;Key Assumptions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;these user firms are identical with respect to all other aspects that bear on their profitability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;none of the players has sufficient knowledge or information to produce the innovation on their own&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it is not possible to reveal the innovation exclusively to the manufacturer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;licensing is not feasible, and that there are no side payments between users and between innovator users and manufacturers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decision variables related to free revealing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the intensity of the competition among users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the degree to which the innovation has a bias favoring the innovating user&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the degree of the manufacturer improvements to the revealed innovation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the cost to user of adopting the improved commercial product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens if change/release the assumptions?
Adaption to behavioral economics game to be played by human? to study impacts of loss aversion, cog
From policy point of view, it would be interesting to study the specific situations where prisoner’s dilemma force them to reveal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html">Harhoff, Dietmar, Joachim Henkel, and Eric von Hippel. “Profiting from Voluntary Information Spillovers: How Users Benefit by Freely Revealing Their Innovations.” Research Policy 32, no. 10 (December 2003): 1753–69. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0048-7333(03)00061-1.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review - How Open Source Software Works - ‘Free’ User-to-User Assistance</title><link href="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/21/Review-Free-user-to-user-assistance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review - How Open Source Software Works - ‘Free’ User-to-User Assistance" /><published>2021-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/21/Review-Free-user-to-user-assistance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/21/Review-Free-user-to-user-assistance.html">&lt;p&gt;Lakhani, Karim R. “How Open Source Software Works: ‘Free’ User-to-User Assistance.” Research Policy, 2003, 21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Research into free and open source software development projects has so far largely focused on how the major tasks of software development are organized and motivated. But a complete project requires the execution of “mundane but necessary” tasks as well. In this paper, we explore how the mundane but necessary task of ﬁeld support is organized in the case of Apache web server software, and why some project participants are motivated to provide this service gratis to others. We ﬁnd that the Apache ﬁeld support system functions effectively. We also ﬁnd that, when we partition the help system into its component tasks, 98% of the effort expended by information providers in fact returns direct learning beneﬁts to those providers. This ﬁnding considerably reduces the puzzle of why information providers are willing to perform this task “for free.” Implications are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-arguments&quot;&gt;Main arguments:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OS community organic field support system function effectively as evidenced in Apache community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost all (98%) the effort expended by community information providers in fact return direct learning benefits to those providers themselves. The main motives to provide help are expected reciprocity, identification with the community cause, gain reputation or enhance career prospects, etc. One average, information providers involve quite small costs/time to answer posted questions. This explains why information providers are willing to perform this supportive task “for free”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-assumptions&quot;&gt;Key assumptions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Participation in the community brings intrinsic private benefits, such as learning, enjoyment and sense of ownership&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It typically took very limited amount of time/efforts to provide most of the off-the-shelf solution information&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does this organic community support work for all type of OS projects (less to learn), developer systems/tools, consumer products/apps? Can it scale to support greater number of users?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How about other types of OS community contributions, testing, bug fixes, and new features? Tons of free data from GitHub API and popular forum software analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Does the quality of community support depend on the type of support system, in this case Usenet help forum, which have evolved into email list, web forum, chatroom, slack/discord, and specialized helpdesk service etc.?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are self-reported motivation and time cost estimation reliable (given the flow experience)?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How does monetary bounty, virtual reward or gamification helps/impact these OS supports work, and customization development request?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html">Lakhani, Karim R. “How Open Source Software Works: ‘Free’ User-to-User Assistance.” Research Policy, 2003, 21.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review - A meta-analytic review of experiments examining the effects of extrinsic rewards on intrinsic motivation</title><link href="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/19/Review-Meta-Analytic-review-of-experiments-examining-effects-extrinsic-rewards-on-intrinsic-motivation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review - A meta-analytic review of experiments examining the effects of extrinsic rewards on intrinsic motivation" /><published>2021-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/19/Review-Meta-Analytic-review-of-experiments-examining-effects-extrinsic-rewards-on-intrinsic-motivation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/19/Review-Meta-Analytic-review-of-experiments-examining-effects-extrinsic-rewards-on-intrinsic-motivation.html">&lt;p&gt;Deci, E. L., Koestner, R., &amp;amp; Ryan, R. M. (1999). A meta-analytic review of experiments examining the effects of extrinsic rewards on intrinsic motivation. Psychological Bulletin, 125(6), 627–668. https:// https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.125.6.627&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A meta-analysis of 128 studies examined the effects of extrinsic rewards on intrinsic motivation. As predicted, engagement-contingent, completion-contingent, and performance-contingent rewards significantly undermined free-choice intrinsic motivation (d = -0.40, -0.36, and -0.28, respectively), as did all rewards, all tangible rewards, and all expected rewards. Engagement-contingent and completioncontingent rewards also significantly undermined self-reported interest (d = -0.15, and —0.17), as did all tangible rewards and all expected rewards. Positive feedback enhanced both free-choice behavior (d = 0.33) and self-reported interest (d = 0.31). Tangible rewards tended to be more detrimental for children than college students, and verbal rewards tended to be less enhancing for children than college students. The authors review 4 previous meta-analyses of this literature and detail how this study’s methods, analyses, and results differed from the previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-arguments&quot;&gt;Main arguments:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A meta-analytic review first reviewed three previous meta-analysis that confirmed the effects of extrinsic rewards undermining intrinsic motivation, two reporting different conclusions, and find the most consistent finding was that task-contingent tangible rewards were detrimental to intrinsic motivation. 128 studies were aggregated to examine different reward types’ effects on intrinsic motivation, with results for the free-choice behavioral measure and the self-reported interest measure. specifically, as predicted, engagement-contingent rewards, completion-contingent rewards, and performance-contingent rewards significantly undermined free-choice intrinsic motivation, as did all rewards, tangible rewards and all expected rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meta-analysis provide strong confirmation that positive feedback enhances intrinsic motivation, which is predicted by cognitive evaluation theory (GET, later evolved into Self-Determination Theory, SDT). Substantially different results from informational vs. controlling verbal reward were found as well as predicted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key takeaway:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reward and contingency types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;verbal (unexpected) reward&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unexpected tangible reward&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;expected tangible reward: task-noncontigent, engagement-contingent, completion-contingent, performance-contingent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common measures for intrinsic motivation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free-choice behavior&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Self-reported interest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CET (Cognitive Evaluation Theory) predicts unexpected, non-controlled reward do not undermine intrinsic motivation, as not perceived as controlling the autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Task-contingent tangible rewards detrimental to intrinsic motivation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expected tangible reward contingent on task performance undermine intrinsic motivation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Informational verbal rewards enhance intrinsic motivation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autonomy, mastery, purpose are the end goals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapter 8 of Reiss’ book of Myths of Intrinsic Motivation &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; were devoted to counter argue this meta-analysis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publication bias: no undermining research tend not to be published&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ceiling effects: many studies were significantly biased in favor of finding undermining effects because they pre-selected people with high levels of interest and due to ceiling effects could not measure when rewards further increased intrinsic interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tips for motivation literature review:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We began by searching the PsycINFO and ERIC databases and recent editions of the Current Contents database for studies published between 1971 and August 1997. Varying combinations of the following search terms were entered: intrinsic motivation, rewards, reinforcement, free time, and free choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Reiss, Steven. Myths of Intrinsic Motivation, 2013. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html">Deci, E. L., Koestner, R., &amp;amp; Ryan, R. M. (1999). A meta-analytic review of experiments examining the effects of extrinsic rewards on intrinsic motivation. Psychological Bulletin, 125(6), 627–668. https:// https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.125.6.627</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review - Intrinsic and Extrinsic Motivations - Classic Definitions and New Directions.</title><link href="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/18/Review-intrinsic-and-extrinsic-motivation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review - Intrinsic and Extrinsic Motivations - Classic Definitions and New Directions." /><published>2021-05-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/18/Review-intrinsic-and-extrinsic-motivation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fast.tk/reviews/2021/05/18/Review-intrinsic-and-extrinsic-motivation.html">&lt;p&gt;Ryan, Richard M., and Edward L. Deci. “Intrinsic and Extrinsic Motivations: Classic Definitions and New Directions.” Contemporary Educational Psychology 25, no. 1 (January 2000): 54–67. https://doi.org/10.1006/ceps.1999.1020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Intrinsic and extrinsic types of motivation have been widely studied, and the distinction between them has shed important light on both developmental and educational practices. In this review we revisit the classic definitions of intrinsic and extrinsic motivation in light of contemporary research and theory. Intrinsic motivation remains an important construct, reflecting the natural human propensity to learn and assimilate. However, extrinsic motivation is argued to vary considerably in its relative autonomy and thus can either reflect external control or true self-regulation. The relations of both classes of motives to basic human needs for autonomy, competence and relatedness are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-arguments&quot;&gt;Main Arguments:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extrinsic motivation: defined as a construct that pertains whenever an activity is done in order to attain some &lt;strong&gt;separable&lt;/strong&gt; outcome. Self-determination Theory (SDT) proposes that extrinsic motivation can vary greatly in the degree of autonomy, ie. extrinsic motivation varies from controlling to autonomous/self-determined continuum)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../images/human.motivation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Fig1. Taxonomy of human motivation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External regulation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introjection: regulated by contingent self-esteem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identification: ego involvement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integration: through self-examination, and value assimilation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More autonomous extrinsic motivation is associated with greater engagement, better performance, and greater psychological well-being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internalization and integration: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Relatedness&lt;/strong&gt; (facilitate identification?), &lt;strong&gt;competence&lt;/strong&gt; facilitate more internalization, and &lt;strong&gt;autonomy&lt;/strong&gt; facilitate integration of behavioral regulation (self-determined), however, feeling of competence alone will not enhance intrinsic motivation unless accompanied by a sense of autonomy. However, as extrinsic regulation become more internalized and self-determined, they do not transform into intrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;Because extrinsically motivated behaviors are not inherently interesting and thus must initially be externally prompted, the primary reason people are likely to be willing to do the behaviors is that they are valued by (their instrumental value) significant others to whom they feel (or would like to feel) connected, whether that be a family, a peer group, or a society. &quot;&lt;/code&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Can this &lt;strong&gt;instrumental value&lt;/strong&gt; behind the extrinsic motivation be somewhat intrinsic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why “as extrinsic regulation become more internalized and self-determined, they do not transform into intrinsic motivation”?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;because behavior motivated by integrated regulation is done for its presumed instrumental value with respect to some outcome that is separate from the behavior, even though it is volitional and valued by the self.&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare SDT with Reiss’s theory of 16 basic desires&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and simply &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow's_hierarchy_of_needs&quot;&gt;Maslow’s Hierarchy of Needs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If extrinsic reward (money) undermines intrinsic reward, why Github Sponsors, open source Patreon, name your own price content download works?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Reiss, Steven. “Multifaceted Nature of Intrinsic Motivation: The Theory of 16 Basic Desires.” Review of General Psychology 8, no. 3 (September 2004): 179–93. https://doi.org/10.1037/1089-2680.8.3.179. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html">Ryan, Richard M., and Edward L. Deci. “Intrinsic and Extrinsic Motivations: Classic Definitions and New Directions.” Contemporary Educational Psychology 25, no. 1 (January 2000): 54–67. https://doi.org/10.1006/ceps.1999.1020.</summary></entry></feed>